

Email Homepage **in** LinkedIn Research Gate GitHub

PROFILE

I am a self-motivated, hardworking, and responsible person who can adapt to all challenging situations. I am motivated by research and able to work well both in a team environment and as well as using own initiative. My research interests include signal and image processing, computer vision, and machine learning with several publications.

EDUCATION

University of Peradeniya, Sri Lanka

2015-2020

B.Sc. in Electrical and Electronic Engineering

GPA: 4.0/4.0 (*Top* of the class)

(The complete degree program was conducted and assessed in English medium and accredited by Washington Accord through IESL)

Kingswood College, Sri Lanka

2012-2014

G.C.E. Advanced Level (Mathematics, Physics, and Chemistry) (Ranked in the **TOP 20** overall in the country)

PUBLICATIONS

CONFERENCE PAPERS

Convolutional Autoencoder for Blind Hyperspectral Image Unmixing D.Y.L. Ranasinghe, S. Herath, H.M.H.K. Weerasooriya, E.M.M.B Ekanayake, G.M.R.I Godaliyadda, H.M.V.R. Herath, M.P.B. Ekanayake

15th Conference on Industrial and Information Systems (Presenter)

Nov 2020

Multispectral imaging for automated fish quality grading

J. M. V. D. B Jayasundara, R. M. L. S Ramanayake, H. M. N B Senarath, S. Herath, G.M.R.I Godaliyadda, H.M.V.R. Herath, M.P.B. Ekanayake

15th Conference on Industrial and Information Systems

Nov 2020

Transmittance Multispectral Imaging for Edible Oil Quality Assessment H.M.H.K. Weerasooriya, H.M.S Lakmal, D.Y.L. Ranasinghe, W.G.C. Bandara, H.M.V.R. Herath, G.M.R.I Godaliyadda, M.P.B. Ekanayake, T. Madhujith

Imaging and Applied Optics Congress, Optical Society of America (Presenter)

Jun 2020

Hyperspectral Imaging Based Method to Identify Potential Limestone Deposits D.Y.L. Ranasinghe, H.M.S Lakmal, H.M.H.K. Weerasooriya, E.M.M.B Ekanayake, G.M.R.I Godaliyadda, H.M.V.R. Herath, M.P.B. Ekanayake 14th Conference on Industrial and Information Systems

Dec 2019

JOURNAL PAPERS

Constrained Nonnegative Matrix Factorization for Blind Hyperspectral Unmixing incorporating Endmember Independence

E.M.M.B. Ekanayake, B. Rathnayake, D.Y.L. Ranasinghe, S. Herath, G.M.R.I. Godaliyadda, H.M.V.R. Herath, M.P.B. Ekanayake IEEE Trans. Geosci. Remote Sens. (under review) Nov 2020

 Quantitative assessment of adulteration and reuse of coconut oil using transmittance multispectral imaging

S. Herath, H.K. Weerasooriya, D.Y.L. Ranasinghe, W.G.C. Bandara, H.M.V.R. Herath, G.M.R.I Godaliyadda, M.P.B. Ekanayake, T. Madhujith Elsevier Journal of Food Engineering (under review) Nov 2020

OTHER PUBLICATIONS

Detecting the Freshness and Class of the Fish using Multispectral Imaging

H.M.S Lakmal, H.M.H.K. Weerasooriya, D.Y.L. Ranasinghe, W.G.C. Bandara, E.M.M.B. Ekanayake H.M.V.R. Herath, G.M.R.I Godaliyadda, M.P.B. Ekanayake IRC 2020, Sri Lanka Technological Campus (Presenter)-Abstract publication Jun 2020

A Multi Spectral Imaging System to Measure Transmittance Spectrum H.M.H.K. Weerasooriya, H.M.S Lakmal, D.Y.L. Ranasinghe, W.G.C. Bandara, H.M.V.R. Herath, G.M.R.I Godaliyadda, M.P.B. Ekanayake. Jan 2020

PROJECTS

2ND YEAR PROJECT 2017-2018

Color to Sound Mapping Device

Patent Sri Lanka No: 20936 (under review)

Color to sound mapping device for visually impaired people

3RD YEAR PROJECT

 Password Protected Locker 2018-2019

Programming pic16f873A from scratch using assembly

Child watch

A low cost for parent-children communication

2019-2020 FINAL YEAR PROJECT

 Hyperspectral Imaging for Remote sensing and agricultural applications Application of algorithms for potential mineral deposit detection

Multispectral Imaging for food quality assessment

Utilize inhouse developed MSI system for coconut oil and fish quality assessment

CONTINUED FINAL YEAR PROJECT

2020-present

 Deep learning for hyperspectral unmixing Application of deep learning for the hyperspectral unmixing problem

Image Processing for food quality Assessment Application of deep learning for real time fish quality assessment

AWARDS

•	C.A. Hewavitharana Memorial Prize for the best performance in Engineering	2020
	Awarded to the best student among all fields of engineering in the faculty	
•	Ceylon Electricity Board Prize for best performance in Electrical & Electrical	ronic
	Engineering	2020
	Awarded to the best student in the field of Electrical and Electronic Engineering	
•	R.H. Paul Prize for Electrical Power & Machines	2020
	Awarded to the best performing student in the electric power and energy re	elated
	subject courses	
•	W.M.G. Fernando Prize for Electronic Communications	2020
	Awarded to the best performing student in the Electronic Communications re	lated
	subject courses	
•	Prof. E.F. Bartholameusz Endowment Award for the best student proje	
	Engineering Mathematics	2020
	Awarded for the best final year project in the Faculty of Engineering wi	th an
	outstanding mathematical background	
•	W.P. Jayasekara Prize for the best student project in Electrical & Electrical	
	Engineering	2020
	Awarded to the best undergraduate final year project in the Department of Elec	trical
	and Electronic Engineering	
•	E.F. Bartholameusz Prize for Engineering Mathematics	2016
	Awarded to the student with highest average mark for the first-year engine	ering
	mathematics modules	204.4
•	Silver Medal-Sri Lankan Physics Olympiad	2014
	Organized by the institute of physics, Sri Lanka.	204.4
•	Devadasan Challenge Trophy for Best All Rounder	2014
	Highest school honor, awarded to one student per each batch	
•	Best result of Science/Math	2014
	Awarded for the best result in GCE Advanced Level Examination in school	

WORK EXPERIENCE

- **Temporary Instructor at University of Peradeniya**Aug 2020- present Conduct tutorial classes on Engineering Mathematics for first year students
- Volunteer Instructor at University of Peradeniya Jan 2020- May 2020 Conduction of laboratory sessions for first year and second year students
- Engineering intern at Paraqum Technologies, Colombo
 Feb 2019- May 2019

 Application and development of several signal processing algorithms for a biomedical project and development of standalone GUI programs
- Engineering trainee at National Water Supply Board, Kandy
 Nov 2017- Jan 2018

 Maintenance of water treatment plants and analysis in power consumption of treatment plants

COMPETITIONS AND EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES				
COMPETITIONS				
 1st Place-aces Hackathon 	2018			
ACES, Faculty of Engineering, University of Peradeniya				
1st Place-Innovators	2016			
Inventors' Club, University of Peradeniya.				
 4th Place-aces Coders v6.0 	2016			
ACES, Faculty of Engineering, University of Peradeniya				
 Best props Manager at Runner-up stage drama 	2019			
Ceylon Dramatic society, University of Peradeniya				
VOLUNTEERING				
Mathematics and Science Instructor	2016,2017			
Workshops organized in Kandy, Ratnapura, and Badulla				
 Volunteer organizer 	2017			
IET Present Around the world				
SPORTS				
1st Runner-up	2009			
All Island School Games-Chess.				
SOCIETIES				
Vice President	2013-2014			
Science Society and Astronomical Society, Kingswood College				
 Member 	2016-2019			
Drama Society and Music Society, University of Peradeniya				

SKILLS	
Programming	Python, MATLAB, C, Assembly
Version Control	Git
Design	Proteus, Eagle, AutoCAD
Graphics	CorelDraw, Adobe Photoshop
Type Setting	LaTeX, MS Office

REFERENCES

Available upon request.